Christina Lytle

Software Developer

Contact



530-306-2545



christina.lytle17@gmail.com



Phoenix, AZ



github.com/Christinalytle



linkedin.com/in/christina-lytle

Skills

Languages

JavaScript Java

HTML/CSS

Frameworks

Bootstrap SpringBoot

Libraries

React JQuery AJAX

Databases

MySQL

APIs

REST JSON

Tools

Postman
Visual Studio Code
Eclipse
Git/GitHub
DBeaver

Professional

CRM Programs Microsoft Office Photoshop/InDesign

Education

Certificate | Back End & Front End Software Development | Gateway Community College | Phoenix, AZ 2020 – 2021

MFA | Arts/Nonprofit Administration | Southern Utah University | Cedar City, UT 2016

BA | Theatre/Business | Humboldt State University | Arcata, CA 2011

Professional Summary

Software Developer with back-end and front-end skills dedicated to creating, maintaining, and testing interactive user-focused software. Experience in database analysis and design, and collaborating with team members to reach department and revenue goals. I'm drawn to software development because of the challenging work, collaborative environment, and endless learning and creative opportunities.

Software Development Experience

Full Stack Software Development Bootcamp

Gateway Community College/Promineo Tech | Phoenix, AZ | 2020-2021

- <u>Social Media App</u>: Social Media website where users can post, comment, and like using React, MongoDB, and GraphQL.
- <u>Hotel Reservation JDBA Project</u>: Hotel room reservation CRUD application using Java, JDBC, and MySQL.
- <u>Game of Thrones Tic-tac-toe</u>: Game of Thrones Tic-tac-toe game using HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, and JQuery.

Professional Experience

Development Systems Analyst

The Phoenix Symphony | Phoenix, AZ | May 2021 – September 2021 (contract)

• **Database Management:** Analyze donor and ticket buyer data from CRM database (Tessitura), create manuals for consistent data input, cleanup donor and ticket buyer records.

Donor Relations, Marketing Manager, and Webmaster

Arizona School for the Arts (ASA) | Phoenix, AZ | July 2016 – October 2020

- Web Development: Project Manager for website redesign with marketing agency implemented new site map, managed content, and maintained website on WordPress. Analyzed Google Analytics to make informed decisions about website content.
- **Database Manager:** Customized CRM database (eTapestry) to track 700 new pledges every year and effectively raise \$1Million each school year with a department of two. Created advanced queries analyzing donor behavior to develop solicitation strategies.
- **KEY ACHIEVEMENTS:** Reached revenue goal every year (\$1M), implemented new website (goasa.org), and new donor database (eTapestry to Raiser'sEdgeNXT).

Audience Development and Marketing Assistant

Utah Shakespeare Festival | Cedar City, UT | May 2014 - May 2016

- **Web Management:** Assisted with website redesign and added content into the new website in SquareSpace.
- **Data Analytics:** Analyzed ten years of ticket sales from CRM to create a new season schedule to allow for more revenue and bigger audiences.
- **KEY ACHIEVEMENTS:** Exceeded the 2015 revenue budget by 2%, grew the number of Instagram followers by 600% from May 2014 to August 2015.